Bahram Mehdi Maravandi Cloud Solutions Manager

+971555464801 - bahi@hey.com - Dubai, Marina



Summary

As a strategic thinker, I have developed a comprehensive and forward-looking vision for cloud adoption, creating a roadmap for realizing the full potential of cloud technologies, identifying areas for improvement, and staying up-to-date on the latest offerings and services from key cloud providers like Microsoft Azure, Amazon AWS, and Oracle OCI.

I have accumulated extensive experience in software development that spans over two decades. During this time, I spent 10+ years in a senior developer role, 5+ years in leadership positions and additionally, I have nearly 5+ years of experience as a cloud architect.

My experience in this field has equipped me with the necessary skills to develop complex enterprise applications using languages such as C# and Python. Furthermore, I have a track record of leading and mentoring teams, facilitating career development opportunities, and promoting continuous learning and a DevOps mindset.

In summary, with my extensive experience in leadership, complex enterprise development, strategic thinking, and DevOps Engineering, I am confident in my ability to contribute value to any organization I join.

Experience

Cloud Solutions Manager at KPIT

January 2021 - Present

As the leader of AD Cloud Services department with over 50 DevOps Engineers, I am responsible for the following:

- Overseeing the hiring process, facilitating career development opportunities, and promoting continuous learning and DevOps mindset within the team.
- Developing a Strategic Vision for Cloud Adoption: I am responsible for creating a comprehensive and forward-looking vision for the organization's cloud adoption strategy. This involves analyzing the current cloud landscape, identifying areas for improvement, and creating a roadmap for realizing the full potential of cloud technologies. By bringing clarity and direction to the organization's cloud efforts, I am helping to ensure that the company remains at the forefront of innovation and can fully leverage the benefits of cloud computing.
- Building Strong Relationships with Key Cloud Providers: Another key responsibility as a Senior Practice Director is to cultivate strong relationships with major cloud providers like Microsoft Azure, Amazon AWS, and Oracle OCI. This involves participating in regular partner meetings, staying up-to-date on the latest offerings and services, and leveraging these relationships to drive innovation and cost savings within the organization. By building close ties with key cloud providers, I am helping to ensure that the company has access to the resources and expertise it needs to fully capitalize on cloud computing.
- Providing resources to AD customers, such as DevOps Engineering support for managing CI pipelines, cloud resources, and creating virtual workspaces.

Senior Lead Developer at Smarthouse Media

November 2014 - December 2020

I contributed to the design and implementation of an Enterprise Content Management System based on Service-Oriented Architecture using a tech stack that included AspNet Core, Angular, and PowerShell-based setup and deployment operations.

We managed the project using Scrum framework and leveraged AzureDevOps for CI and release pipelines, Docker, Docker Compose, and Azure Kubernetes Service (AKS) to enable efficient and effective development processes.

Technical Lead at Unisys

October 2011 - November 2014

I contributed to Release Management and Continuous Integration, and worked on an Oracle-based Windows application for Traffic Management, where I was responsible for analyzing functional specifications and implementing a Loan Management Application for the web.

Additionally, I led the design and implementation of the Austrian Telecom Point of Sales Application for the web.

Senior Developer Technical Lead at Greentube

August 2008 - September 2011

As Senior Lead Developer, I worked on an OpenX based Campaign Management system for a 3D Game.

In addition, I was responsible for the Security and Rights Management of companies internal web applications.

I led the design and implementation of the main website and added Release Management and Continuous Integration pipelines.

I designed and implemented a Gaming B2B Service API for communicating with external customers.

I was also responsible for recruiting new members to the team and providing architecture advice.

Senior Developer at bwin

February 2001 - June 2005

As a Senior Developer, I designed and implemented a Customer Support web application.

I Developed a template based Content Management Web Application.

I Developed a Newsletter Generator, including a Mass Mailer, Data Warehouse, related Content Templates, and a Bounce Mail handler.

I Developed a Promotion Framework for the Bet Engine from scratch.

I Developed a Web Application Framework for internal Service applications, including templates and Role based right management.

Software Developer at Eurest

June 1996 - January 2001

As a Software Developer, I designed and Implemented a comprehensive ERP Application including:

- A Cash book which records all daily income and expenses with monthly closure of entries.
- Recording all delivery notes for registered suppliers.
- Recording Supplier Invoices.
- Inventory recording of all available products.
- Supplier Registry.
- A comprehensive list of all related Controlling Reports.

In addition, I automated the Importing of Enterprise-wide monthly closure data to IBM AS/400.

Education

Technical University of Vienna Bachelor of Science (BS), Computer Science

Certifications

AWS Solutions Architect - Associate



Mehdi Maravandi

has successfully completed the AWS Certification requirements and has achieved their:

AWS Certified Solutions Architect - Associate

Issue Date Sep 29, 2020

Expiration Date Sep 29, 2023 Maureen Jonesgan

Maureen Lonergan
Director, Training and Certification

Validation Number VX44G5DJK1111F3J Validate at: http://aws.amazon.com/verification